STEPHANIE PROVENCE

Fair Oaks, CA 916-531-0630 smprovence22@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/smprovence/ GitHub: https://github.com/smprov22/ Portfolio: https://sprovence-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A web designer/developer with a strong affinity for design. Spent over 10 years in the film and television industry and have strong storytelling abilities and excel in making things as user friendly as possible. Experience with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, Firebase, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars, Sequelize, mySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, and React. Strong ability to collaborate and problem solve served me well in the film industry and is also very relevant in web design and development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Tools: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, Firebase, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars, Sequelize, mySQL, Mongo, Mongoose, and React

Design Software: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe inDesign, Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects.

PROJECTS

Project Title — Chatbot Concierge

August 2019

Many budget and chain hotels operate without a concierge but hotel patrons still want to know about activities that they can do in the local area. Many activities that give a town or city character are free but there is no good resource to find these activities. We built a website to show local activities tailored to the guest with 5 questions. Our stretch goal is to use this to create an Alexa skill to work with our app/site.

- Tools Used: React, CSS3, Javascript, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Express.js, Passport.js
- https://chatbot-concierge.herokuapp.com/
- https://github.com/smprov22/Chatbot-Concierge

Project Title — Rapid Logger

July 2019

The Rapid Logger is designed to be a personal task management system that helps capture and organize tasks/events/thoughts quickly and easily. The brain often doesn't work in an orderly fashion so organizing a task manager that way doesn't always work. The rapid logger allows the user to quickly type in their events/tasks/notes using designated hotkeys and then they are automatically sorted in the task manager.

- Tools Used: HTML5, CSS3, Materialize, Javascript, jQuery, MySQL, Node.js, Express,js, Handlebars, Passport.js, Sequelize
- https://rapid-logger.herokuapp.com/
- https://github.com/smprov22/Rapid-Logger

Project Title — TRVL

May 2019

A one-stop-shop travel website where users can search a variety of destinations with high quality photos, weather information, and a map with information specific to the city. Users can also compare their current search with previous searches.

- Tools Used: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Firebase, Bootstrap
- https://smprov22.github.io/TRVL./
- https://github.com/smprov22/TRVL.

EXPERIENCE

CBS - Writer/Producer

Sacramento, CA

Aug 2019 - present

- Write and produce nightly topicals for the 4pm, 6:30pm,and 10pm news
- Work with creative director to write the most interesting tease possible
- Communicate with news team and anchors to stay up to date on current stories

Hestan Cue - Editor

Napa, CA

July 2018 - March 2019

- Edited recipe videos and social media videos for the Hestan Cue app and social media pages
- Streamlined the shooting and editing process to save time and resources
- Tools Used: Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop

Bix Pix Entertainment - Editor - Tumble Leaf

Sun Valley, CA

February 2016 - March 2018

- Assembled animatics with the director and storyboard team
- Worked closely with visual effects team to implement vfx into each episode
- Tumble Leaf won 3 Annie Awards and 13 Daytime Emmy Awards
- Tools Used: Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects

Thrive Market - Lead Video Editor/Producer

Marina Del Rey, CA

October 2015 - February 2016

- Launched the video channel for Thrive Market
- Edited healthy living, food, and documentary videos
- Maintained the schedule and managed other editors
- Tools Used: Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop

Tastemade - Video Editor/Producer

Santa Monica, CA

October 2014 - October 2015

- Worked with a team of editors on food, travel and branded videos
- Partnered with companies such as Chase, Google, American Express, Chrysler, Pepsi, Hyundai
- Tools Used: Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop

PopSugar - Lead Video Editor

Santa Monica, CA

December 2009 - April 2012

- Lead Editor for the beauty channel
- Led video team at NY fashion week for 3 seasons where I edited and posted 100+ videos in 8 days
- Trained new editors to ensure their editing style was "on brand"
- Tools Used: Final Cut Pro, Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop

EDUCATION

Certificate - Full Stack Developer

UC Davis Coding Bootcamp

Davis. CA - 2019

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, Firebase, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars, Sequelize, mySQL, Mongo, Mongoose, and React

California State University Monterey Bay, Seaside, CA — BA in Cinema Arts - 2007

Major in Film Studies with an Emphasis in Editing. Graduated Magna Cum Laude.